# Brian Evans - FRM, CQF

Investment professional and chartered engineer with extensive work experience in the venture capital, private equity, commodities and energy space. Experience in leading, sourcing, due diligence, negotiating, and managing investments in Vertically-Focused Technologies, startup seeds and series A-D investments, Fintech, Cleantech, and Emerging Technology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Sky High VC Fund,** London/Cayman/Uruguay — Partner

2021 - PRESENT

Partner dedicated to seed and series A-D funding of startups. Develop and manage deals, execute transactions and define portfolio economics and control. Structure capitalization table including pre/post money valuations. Define equity classes, capital structure and budgeting, valuation and percentage of ownership.

Responsible for all stages of private capital investment including product specific diligence, startup and project sponsorship, market analysis, team screening and transactions. Conduct sector, vertical and product research, development of investment themes, modeling, due diligence, financial and accounting structuring, negotiation and investment committee presentations.

Develop an objective perspective of covered sectors, including managing and building brand and relationships with: institutional investors, VC firms, startup accelerators, founders, and other members of the venture ecosystem. AUM U\$D 50 MM.

# Warburg Pincus PE, London/NY — Principal

2019 - 2021

Responsible for financial, operational conditions and industry dynamics of assigned portfolio companies. Optimize capital structure, improve asset performance and assist with quarterly reviews with the general partners and investors.

Manage day to day work of existing portfolio of companies, through executive committee meetings, board and management meetings, advisory work, analysis and review with respective working teams. Monitor and improve income statements, balance sheet and cash flow statements of invested companies.

Proactively work with the management and board of portfolio companies (in a board/asset manager capacity) to execute growth and operational improvement strategies. Total budget. AUM U\$D 1 - 1.5 Bn.

# **ORSTED Power**, Denmark — Treasury and Corporate Finance

2015 - 2019

Worked in finance, capital structure and capital budgeting. M&A team leader including divestment transactions to institutional investors, mutual funds, pensions funds, insurance companies. Asset management and portfolio allocation responsibility. Responsible for IRR/WACC/NPV and project finance. AUM EUR 5 Bn.

## **GLENCORE**, London — Corporate Finance

2013 - 2015

Finance specialist working on capital structure and cost control. Lead CAPEX and OPEX budgeting and forecasting for major energy projects in Asia and Africa. Project size range of GBP 50 MM to GBP 1 Bn.

#### **SKILLS**

Private Equity deals
Financial modeling
Valuations: DCF, DDM/TV
Board Director/CFO
Relative valuations
Comps/recent transactions
Exit strategies/IPO/M&A
Due diligence
Capitalization tables
Fund raising
Asset Management

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

FRM (GARP)
CQF (Fitch ratings)
ERP (GARP)
Chartered Engineer (IMechE)

## **LANGUAGES**

English and Spanish, bilingual.

# **Repsol,** Spain/Brazil/Argentina — *Project finance and Engineering*

2009 - 2013

Engineering and project finance on major energy projects including development and exploration assets, greenfield and brownfield developments. Budget of U\$D 50 MM to U\$D 100 MM.

### **EDUCATION**

**University of Cambridge**, UK — MBA (finance)

2014 - 2015

**Newcastle University**, UK — *MSc Mechanical Engineering* 

2011 - 2012

Catholic University, Argentina — BSc Environmental Engineering

2004 - 2009